Tsu-Jui (Ray) Fu

About Me

I am currently a 2nd-year Ph.D. student at UCSB CS, advised by William Wang. My research interest lies in natural language processing (NLP) and computer vision (CV). Primarily, I work on language grounding and interacting with environments using language. Besides, I am also interested in information extraction and video analysis. My goal is to bridge the gap between vision and language via the AI system.

Education

2019-now Ph.D. at University of California, Santa Barbara, Computer Science, CA, USA.

Advisor: William Yang Wang

2014–2018 B.S. at National Tsing-Hua University, Computer Science, Hsinchu, Taiwan.

Advisor: Shan-Hung Wu, Chun-Yi Lee, and Hwann-Tzong Chen

Experience

2019-now UCSB NLP, Research Assistant, CA, USA.

Advisor: William Yang Wang

Summer 2021 Microsoft Azure AI, Research Intern, WA, USA.

Advisor: Linjie Li and Zhe Gan

Summer 2020 Microsoft Research, Research Intern, WA, USA.

Advisor: Yale Song and Daniel McDuff

Summer 2019 Preferred Networks, Research Intern, Tokyo, Japan.

Advisor: Yuta Tsuboi and Jason Naradowsky

2017–2019 Academia Sinica CKIP Lab, Research Assistant, Taipei, Taiwan.

Advisor: Wei-Yun Ma

2017–2018 **NTHU ELSA Lab**, Research Assistant, Hsinchu, Taiwan.

Advisor: Chun-Yi Lee

2017–2018 Umbo Computer Vision, Research Collaboration, Taipei, Taiwan.

Advisor: Hwann-Tzong Chen

Summer 2017 Academia Sinica CKIP Lab, Research Intern, Taipei, Taiwan.

Advisor: Wei-Yun Ma

Publications

2021 H-FND: Hierarchical False-Negative Denoising for Robust Distantly-Supervised Relation Extraction.

Tsu-Jui Fu*, Jhih-Wei Chen*, Chen-Kang Lee, and Wei-Yun Ma Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL), 2021 (Findings)

2021 Semi-Supervised Policy Initialization for Playing Games with Language Hints.

Tsu-Jui Fu and William Yang Wang

North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL), 2021 (Short)

2021 L2C: Describing Visual Differences Needs Semantic Understanding of Individuals.

An Yang, Xin Wang, Tsu-Jui Fu, and William Yang Wang

European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL), 2021 (Short)

2021 Multimodal Style Transfer Learning for Outdoor Vision-and-Language Navigation.

Wanrong Zhu, Xin Wang, **Tsu-Jui Fu**, An Yan, Pradyumna Narayana, Kazoo Sone, Sugato Basu, and William Yang Wang

European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL), 2021 (Long)

2020 SSCR: Iterative Language-Based Image Editing via Self-Supervised Counterfactual Reasoning.

Tsu-Jui Fu, Xin Eric Wang, Scott Grafton, Miguel Eckstein, and William Yang Wang Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (**EMNLP**), 2020 (Long)

2020 Counterfactual Vision-and-Language Navigation via Adversarial Path Sampler.

Tsu-Jui Fu, Xin Eric Wang, Matthew Peterson, Scott Grafton, Miguel Eckstein, and William Yang Wang European Conference on Computer Vision (**ECCV**), 2020 (**Spotlight**)

2020 Why Attention? Analyzing and Remedying BiLSTM Deficiency in Modeling Cross-Context for NER.

Peng-Hsuan Li, **Tsu-Jui Fu**, and Wei-Yun Ma AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (**AAAI**), 2020 (**Oral**)

2019 A Distributed Scheme for Accelerating Semantic Video Segmentation on An Embedded Cluster.

Tsu-Jui Fu*, Hsuan-Kung Yang*, Kuan-Wei Ho, Po-Han Chiang and Chun-Yi Lee International Conference on Computer Design (**ICCD**), 2019 (**Oral**)

2019 Adversarial Active Exploration for Inverse Dynamics Model Learning.

Zhang-Wei Hong, **Tsu-Jui Fu**, Tzu-Yun Shann, Yi-Hsiang Chang, and Chun-Yi Lee Conference on Robot Learning (**CoRL**), 2019 (**Oral**)

2019 GraphRel: Modeling Text as Relational Graphs for Joint Entity and Relation Extraction.

Tsu-Jui Fu, Peng-Hsuan Li, and Wei-Yun Ma

Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL), 2019 (Long)

2019 Attentive and Adversarial Learning for Video Summarization.

Tsu-Jui Fu, Shao-Heng Tai, and Hwann-Tzong Chen Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2019 (Oral)

2018 Region-Semantics Preserving Image Synthesis.

Kang-Jun Liu, **Tsu-Jui Fu**, and Shan-Hung Wu Asian Conference on Computer Vision (**ACCV**), 2018

2018 Diversity-Driven Exploration Strategy for Deep Reinforcement Learning.

Zhang-Wei Hong, Tzu-Yun Shann, Shih-Yang Su, Yi-Hsiang Chang, **Tsu-Jui Fu**, and Chun-Yi Lee Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (**NeurIPS**), 2018

2018 Speed Reading: Learning to Read ForBackward via Shuttle.

Tsu-Jui Fu and Wei-Yun Ma

Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), 2018 (Long)

2018 Dynamic Video Segmentation Network.

Yu-Syuan Xu, **Tsu-Jui Fu***, Hsuan-Kung Yang*, and Chun-Yi Lee Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (**CVPR**), 2018

2019 Learning from Observation-Only Demonstration for Task-Oriented Language Grounding via Self-Examination.

Tsu-Jui Fu, Yuta Tsuboi, Sosuke Kobayashi, and Yuta Kikuchi Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (**NeurIPS**), 2019 (ViGIL Workshop)

2018 Visual Relationship Prediction via Label Clustering and Incorporation of Depth Information.

Hsuan-Kung Yang, An-Chieh Cheng, Kuan-Wei Ho, **Tsu-Jui Fu**, and Chun-Yi Lee European Conference on Computer Vision (**ECCV**), 2018 (PIC Workshop)

2021 Language-Driven Image Style Transfer.

Tsu-Jui Fu, Xin Eric Wang, and William Yang Wang

2021 Language-based Video Editing via Multi-Modal Multi-Level Transformer.

Tsu-Jui Fu, Xin Eric Wang, Scott Grafton, Miguel Eckstein, and William Yang Wang

- 2021 **DOC2PPT: Automatic Presentation Slides Generation from Scientific Documents**. **Tsu-Jui Fu**, William Yang Wang, Daniel McDuff, and Yale Song
- 2018 Dialogue-based Diverse Travel Itinerary Recommendation System via Path Sampling. Tsu-Jui Fu, Yu-Han Chen, Huan-Cheng Chang, and Wei-Yun Ma

Organizing

Workshop on Advances in Language and Vision Research (ALVR).

North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (NAACL), 2021

Awards

- Spring 2019 Third Place, Formosa Grand Challenge, Ministry of Science and Technology (MOST), Taiwan.
- Summer 2018 Second Place, Person In Context Challenge, ECCV 2018.
 - Spring 2018 **Outstanding Students Conference Travel Grant**, Foundation For The Advancement of Outstanding Scholarship (FAOS), Taiwan.

Teaching

- Summer 2018 Teaching Assistant, Vision and Learning Summer School, National Tsing-Hua University.
 - Spring 2018 Teaching Assistant, Nvidia Deep Learning Workshop, National Central University.
 - Fall 2017 **Teaching Assistant**, CS565600 Deep Learning, National Tsing-Hua University.
 - Fall 2017 **Teaching Assistant**, CS210401 Hardware Design and Lab, National Tsing-Hua University.